<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Jean Pierre Charalambos]]></title>
  <link href="http://nakednous.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nakednous.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-02T15:24:45-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://nakednous.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jean Pierre Charalambos]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proscene v2.0.0-beta2 Released]]></title>
    <link href="http://nakednous.github.io/blog/2014/03/23/proscene-v2-dot-0-0-beta2-released/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-23T19:24:12-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://nakednous.github.io/blog/2014/03/23/proscene-v2-dot-0-0-beta2-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Proscene v2.0.0-beta2 is out. Download it <a href="https://github.com/remixlab/proscene/releases/download/v-2.0.0-beta.2/proscene-2.0.0-beta.2.zip">here</a> 
and extract it to your sketchbook <code>libraries</code> folder (automatic importing <em>Proscene</em> from your PDE is only available for stable releases, currently v-1.2.0).</p>

<p>This release fixes a nasty bug introduced in the <a href="http://nakednous.github.io/blog/2014/03/22/proscene-v2-dot-0-0-beta1-released/">previous beta</a> which made
the scene dissapear when dragging with the mouse center button. Thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/AmnonOwed/media">Amnon Owed</a> for reporting it.
We encourage all Proscene2 users to upgrade to this version.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proscene v2.0.0-beta1 Released]]></title>
    <link href="http://nakednous.github.io/blog/2014/03/22/proscene-v2-dot-0-0-beta1-released/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-22T18:04:51-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://nakednous.github.io/blog/2014/03/22/proscene-v2-dot-0-0-beta1-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Proscene v2.0.0-beta1 is out. Download it <a href="https://github.com/remixlab/proscene/releases/download/v-2.0.0-beta.1/proscene-2.0.0-beta.1.zip">here</a> 
and extract it to your sketchbook <code>libraries</code> folder (automatic importing <em>Proscene</em> from your PDE is only available for stable releases, currently v-1.2.0).</p>

<p>The new API has been thoroughly reviewed and documented and may be considered frozen (unless something unexpected requiring a fix happens).
Check it out <a href="http://otrolado.info/prosceneApi/">here</a>. We are greatful to <a href="http://www.alcys.com/">Jacques Maire</a> for contributing the new Proscene logo
code which is a <a href="http://www.mathcurve.com/courbes3d/solenoidtoric/solenoidtoric.shtml">torus solenoid</a>.</p>

<p>The new library architecture comprises the following packages:</p>

<h2 id="fpstiminghttpsgithubcomremixlabfpstimingtree"><a href="https://github.com/remixlab/fpstiming_tree">FPSTiming</a></h2>

<p>A single-threaded <a href="http://otrolado.info/prosceneApi/remixlab/fpstiming/TimingHandler.html">timing handler</a> providing timers and animators.
The package may be run stand-alone and it’s provided in its <a href="https://github.com/remixlab/fpstiming_tree">own tree</a>.</p>

<h2 id="biashttpsgithubcomremixlabbiastree"><a href="https://github.com/remixlab/bias_tree">BIAS</a></h2>

<p>An <a href="http://otrolado.info/prosceneApi/remixlab/bias/core/InputHandler.html">input handler</a> providing means to translate event input data into high-level
user-defined actions. The package represents the new Proscene event back-end, but it may be run stand-alone and it’s provided in its
<a href="https://github.com/remixlab/bias_tree">own tree</a> too.</p>

<h2 id="dandelionhttpsgithubcomremixlabdandeliontree"><a href="https://github.com/remixlab/dandelion_tree">Dandelion</a></h2>

<p>Package implementing all sorts of (motion) <a href="http://otrolado.info/prosceneApi/remixlab/dandelion/core/Constants.DandelionAction.html">actions</a> on Frames
(coordinate systems). Dandelion depends on both, FPSTiming and BIAS. <!--- next version should mention it is language agnostic and the JS approach... --></p>

<h2 id="proscene">Proscene</h2>

<p>Package holding a single class (the <a href="http://otrolado.info/prosceneApi/remixlab/proscene/Scene.html">Scene</a>) which represents an interface between Dandelion
and Processing.</p>

<p>Although the (high-level) <a href="http://otrolado.info/prosceneApi/remixlab/proscene/Scene.html">Scene API</a> has been re-factored, Proscene1.x users may stick to it
and feel at home. Most of the examples ported from Proscene1.x look even simpler now. They all have been re-organized reflecting the new structure to
attract those willing to digg into the inners of the new architecture.</p>

<p>Expect for one or two more betas before the final release. We plan to improve the docs, particularly that of the examples. Please report any bug or issue you
may find and help us make the upcoming proscene2 as polished as possible.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proscene v2.0.0-alpha3 Released]]></title>
    <link href="http://nakednous.github.io/blog/2014/01/28/proscene-v2-dot-0-0-alpha3-released/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-28T18:54:47-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://nakednous.github.io/blog/2014/01/28/proscene-v2-dot-0-0-alpha3-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Proscene v2.0.0-alpha3 is out. Download it <a href="https://github.com/remixlab/proscene/releases/download/v-2.0.0-alpha.3/proscene-2.0.0-alpha.3.zip">here</a> 
and extract it to your sketchbook <code>libraries</code> folder (automatic importing <em>proscene</em> from your PDE is only available for stable releases, currently v-1.2.0).</p>

<p>This release completes the main functionality expected in proscene2 and also focuses on API stabilization. Thanks to collaborations with
experimental computational designer <a href="https://twitter.com/AmnonOwed/media">Amnon Owed</a>, to whom we’re greatful, we’ve polished the
KeyFrameInterpolator sub-system. We’ve also implemented view frustum 2D culling routines
(please refer to the new example: <code>TwoD.WindowCulling</code>), thus completing the 2D functionality.</p>

<p>We now enter the beta (sub)cycle which will focus on documentation completeness and bug fixing, to make the upcoming proscene2 as
polished as possible.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proscene v2.0.0-alpha2 released]]></title>
    <link href="http://nakednous.github.io/blog/2013/11/26/proscene-v2-dot-0-0-alpha2-released/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-26T17:13:29-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://nakednous.github.io/blog/2013/11/26/proscene-v2-dot-0-0-alpha2-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Proscene v2.0.0-alpha2 is out. Download it <a href="https://github.com/remixlab/proscene/releases/download/v-2.0.0-alpha.2/proscene-2.0.0-alpha.2.zip">here</a> 
and extract it to your sketchbook <code>libraries</code> folder (automatic importing <em>proscene</em> from your PDE is only available for stable releases, currently v-1.2.0).</p>

<p>Respect to the <a href="http://nakednous.github.io/blog/2013/10/26/proscene-v2-dot-0-0-alpha1-released/">first alpha</a>, this release implements full matrix handling in core,
making possible to perform all geometry transformations directly by proscene2. Actually, this is part of a more general idea: to make it
possible to run proscene2 within other contexts different than Processing. Please refer to the new example Basics.MatrixShader.
I hope to give more details here soon.</p>

<p>Currently, we are performing more experiments to decide what experimental stuff will make it into the upcoming cycle. We plan to release a pair or
so of more alphas with our results before entering beta stage.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proscene v2.0.0-alpha1 released]]></title>
    <link href="http://nakednous.github.io/blog/2013/10/26/proscene-v2-dot-0-0-alpha1-released/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-26T15:23:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://nakednous.github.io/blog/2013/10/26/proscene-v2-dot-0-0-alpha1-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I’m releasing the first alpha of what will hopefully become <em>proscene2</em>. For the impatient, <a href="https://github.com/remixlab/proscene/releases/download/v-2.0.0-alpha.1/proscene-2.0.0-alpha.1.zip">download it</a> and extract it to your sketchbook <code>libraries</code> folder (automatic importing <em>proscene</em> from your PDE is only available for stable releases, currently v-1.2.0). Even though the library has almost been completely rewritten from the ground up, you will find most of the current examples with some minor changes, plus a whole bunch of new ones. There’s also a new project <a href="http://otrolado.info/">home</a> and its code is now kindly hosted at <a href="https://github.com/remixlab">github</a>. Read on for some more details.</p>

<h2 id="motivation">Motivation</h2>

<p>Some years ago <em>Proscene</em> was firstly designed to ease interactivity of 3D <em>Processing</em> scenes through standard input devices: mouse and keyboard. Then at some point when we noticed that some of you guys were interacting within your sketches using “non-standard” Human Interface Devices (HIDs), we decided to add some basic support to them, but the code never really makes it to <em>Proscene’s</em> core: the <code>iFrame</code> class hierarchy. The reason for that being that <code>iFrames</code> and (standard) input events were tightly coupled. Our first <em>Proscene</em> design also lacked providing means to interact using a touch device, mainly because back in 2010 when it was first released, there wasn’t a Processing “android mode”. On the other hand, as with any other <em>Processing</em> library, publishing a sketch online was a matter of exporting it as a java applet. However, this is no longer the case and, as most of you probably know, Java-Script (JS) has almost ended up replacing java applets in <em>Processing2</em>.</p>

<h2 id="challenges-for-the-proscene2-cycle">Challenges for the Proscene2 cycle</h2>

<ol>
  <li>Add 2D <code>Scene</code> mode (e.g., <code>size(640, 360, P2D); scene = new Scene(this);</code>). Yes, it’s not part of the above motivation, but that would be cool ;)</li>
  <li>Allow adding a new HID to interact with a 2D or 3D scene as simple as possible, without hindering the customization flexibility as it is found with standard devices.</li>
  <li>Support other <em>Processing</em> modes such as JS and/or Android.</li>
</ol>

<p>and while it has been progress for the third challenge, this release only covers the first two of them.</p>

<h2 id="approach">Approach</h2>

<ol>
  <li>2D interactivity required <code>scaling</code> to be added to <code>iFrames</code> which are now defined by their <code>position</code>, <code>orientation</code> and (now) <code>scaling</code>. As a result, moving the viewpoint around, picking and manipulating objects, adding keyframes to a camera path, etc., are all now possible in 2D too.</li>
  <li>We completely decoupled the handling of HIDs from the set of <em>actions</em> (all sorts of <code>iFrame</code> manipulations) supported by <em>Proscene</em>, by defining a set of <em>virtual events</em> (called <code>TerseEvents</code>) which represents an interface between them. An important <code>TerseEvent</code> specialization is a <code>MotionEvent</code> which is defined according to its degrees-of-freedom (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Degrees_of_freedom_(mechanics)">DOFs</a>), making it particularly suitable to applications requiring all sorts of kinematics computations, such as those involved in <code>iFrame</code> manipulations. Adding an HID thus “<em>only</em>” requires reducing hardware input events to <code>MotionEvents</code>, from which all <em>Proscene</em> actions are now implemented.</li>
</ol>

<p>Expect more technical details regarding <em>Proscene2</em> and its new package structure with the next pre-releases.</p>

<h2 id="current-status-why-we-call-it-alpha1">Current status: why we call it <em>alpha.1</em>?</h2>

<ol>
  <li>JS mode: work-in-progress.</li>
  <li>Examples documentation: mostly missing. However all the examples seem to run fine here (<a href="https://www.archlinux.org/">archlinux</a> and <em>Processing-2.1b1</em>).</li>
  <li>API docs: broken and incomplete.</li>
  <li>Advanced examples need more polishing.</li>
</ol>

<p>This release is mainly aimed at testers and enthusiasts that wanna try the new features from perfectly well undocumented examples ;)</p>

<h2 id="acknowledgements">Acknowledgements</h2>

<p>Thanks to  <a href="http://edumo.net/">Eduardo Moriana</a> and <a href="http://maparrar.github.io/">Miguel Parra</a> for their contributions with the <a href="http://www.tuio.org/">TUIO</a>-based touch and kinect interfaces, respectively.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
